Fabian Brachetta

Nationality:

- ·Italian
- Argentinian

Education:

- •MBA University of Wales UK
- •B. Comm Marketing UAI Universidad Abierta Interamericana - Argentina
- •Disruptive Strategy Certificate - Harvard Business School Online
- ·Certified Scrum Professional Product Owner - Scrum.org
- •Full Stack Developer -Code Institute (In course)

Languages:

- •English
- Spanish
- ·Italian

What am I proud of?

- •Successfully opened new markets around the world
- •Worked in different countries and cultures
- •Created a company that won over competition and serviced leading brands
- Made professional and personal connections worldwide
- •Consistently grew revenue and GPM% in diverse industries

Personal Interests

- ·Software Development
- ·Agile Scrum
- •Pop Art
- •Private Pilot +500 h.
- ·Scuba Diving

Contact:

T:+31(0)6 42813400

E: brachetta@gmail.com Linkedin www.linkedin.com/ in/brachetta



Summary

Passionate about international business, software development and Agile & Scrum with experience in Europe, Middle East, Africa and China and success stories around the world.

I have directed and helped companies and teams to achieve sustainable growth by defining ambitious goals as well as monitoring implementation and execution of complex projects.

I am a team player who can make a clear assessment of opportunities, define how it should be best pursued and subsequently devise an action plan with clear deliverables for success.

A self-starter, I am resourceful in establishing new relations that clients and teams trust and value, creating the conditions in which we are able to grow together.

The clients in my portfolio are sophisticated and commercially astute, including familiar names such as Carrefour, Adidas, Sony, as well as some complex technology and Telecom companies like NOKIA, Huawei, Etisalat and DU.

I have worked in very different fields, countries and cultures thereby validating my skills across different sectors and industries.

Founder of www.exxim.net + www.moblogic.com + Cartoonist: www.brachetta.nl

Experience

2019 - Present: Global Head Subscriptions at GrandVision NV - Amsterdam, The Netherlands.

- Product Owner of Global Subscription program to enhance digital experience across GrandVision's international banners and over 7500 stores
- Implementation of ZUORA subscription platform in a complex architecture with legacy systems.
- Launch products with an infinite amount of pricing & packaging flexibility.
- Automate all billing, accounting, collections and logistic operations.

2017 - 2018: Global Head Franchising at GrandVision NV - Amsterdam, The Netherlands.

- Delivered a ready to use Franchise Proposition for a hard franchise model in standalone Solaris stores in both existing and new markets.
- Developed a brand new concept with a highly innovative commercial model targeting various new sales channels outside optical stores.

2014 - Present: Founder/Non Executive Director at EXXIM LLC - Dubai, United Arab Emirates

- EXXIM provides integral merchandising solutions to leading companies in the Middle East and Africa, advising clients on how to maximise sales while reducing shrinkage with a better customer experience, resulting in profits increase.
- Achieved in year one over 60% of the UAE marketshare of retail open merchandising solutions.
- Developed a strong relationship with most consumer electronic brands, hypermarkets and Telcos in MEA including Axiom Telecom, Huawei, LG, Plugins, Emax, Geant, Lulu, Lenovo, Grand Stores, Microsoft, Nike, Adidas, SONY and Carrefour.

2010 - 2014: Regional Director META at InVue Security Products - Dubai, UAE

- Managed Middle East, Turkey and Africa, a challenging territory which turned into a key region for the company as one of the fastest growing in the world.
- Increased the turnover of the area by over 200% achieving USD 8M while keeping GPM above 50% consistently exceeding yearly goals.
- Forged a trusted relationship with leading telcos across the region including Du, Etisalat, Meditel, Ooredoo, Vodafone, Turkcell, Vodacom, Safaricom and more.
- Recruited an extended network of new exclusive distributors, creating revenue stream in previously underdeveloped areas such as Lebanon, Egypt, Tunisia and Morocco.

2007 - 2009: Business Director at Masterfranchisers FZCO - Dubai, UAE / Riyadh, KSA

 Responsible of brand expansion for brands including Hunkemuller (Lingerie - The Netherlands), Carpisa (Leather handbags - Italy), Stefanel (Fashion - Italy), Padini, Seed (Fashion - Malaysia), Jysk (Furniture - Denmark), Bed & Bath (KSA), Trios (Fast Food - Australia), NZN (Ice Cream - New Zealand).

2004 - 2007: Business Development Director + Franchisee Recruiter EMEA at Subway Int'l. BV - Amsterdam, The Netherlands

- Subway is the world restaurant leader in terms of store count and a pioneer in franchising with over 44,000 outlets worldwide.
- Nominated to Best Franchise Manager Managers Network Netherlands.
- During my tenure, the number of stores opened/year Increased 220% from 695 in year 2004 to 1524 outlets opened in 2006 setting a record of openings at the time.
- In charge of recruitment of new area developers to ensure company's expansion in key geographic areas.